请注意
Look alive.
目标距离315英里 接近中
Contact appears to be heading 315 miles.
速度430 天使 高度约 2000
Speed 430, Angels. Approximately 2, 000.
汽车世界
World of Cars
飞机总动员
Planes
他在磨蹭什么?
What's taking this guy so long?
他真有自己说的那么厉害吗?
Is he really as good as they say he is?
不 是更厉害
No. Better.
哦 耶!
Oh. Yeah!
瞧! 那是谁?
Whoa! Who was that?
早上好 姑娘们 输了可别哭鼻子啊
Why, hello, ladies. Are you ready to lose?
最后飞到水塔的飞机给其他飞机买油
Last one to the water tower buys a round of fuel.
这样吧 我让你们先飞一段
Tell you what, I'll give you guys a head start.
- 你们用得上的  - 等着瞧 失败者
- You're going to need it.  - Later, loser.
一 一千 二... 哦 好了
One one-thousand, two one... oh, that's enough.
再见了 笨蛋!
See ya, suckers!
尝尝我的...
Eat my...
- 达斯迪!  - 哦! 啊...
- Dusty!  - Oh! Aw...
你又在做白日梦 给我小心点
Pay attention. You're daydreaming again.
白日梦? 没 没!
Me? No, no, no! No.
哦 好吧 有
Okay, yes.
别这样 利巴顿
But, you know, come on, Leadbottom.
这活有多难?
Really? How hard is this?
就是往前飞 转弯 再往前飞 再转弯
Fly straight, turn around. Fly straight, turn around.
你是在瞧不起伟大的空中喷洒艺术吗?
Are you disrespecting the sweet science of aerial application?
我可不想当一辈子作物喷粉机
Look, I am more than just a crop duster.
别再跟我念叨
Don't go flap-jawing
你那个花球之翼
about that Flings Around the Planet air racing nonsense again.
抱歉 那叫环球之翼飞行大赛
Excuse me, it is called the Wings Around the Globe Rally.
看在彼得比尔特牌汽车的份儿上!
For the love of Peterbilt!
我没胡说 我的转弯平稳
And it's not nonsense. I've got a tight turn radius
功率质量比也很高
and a high power-to-weight ratio.
- 你知道你还有什么吗?  - 什么?
- You know what else you got?  - What?
脑袋有包!
A screw loose!
为什么你不想给作物喷粉?
I mean, why would you want to give up crop-dusting?
蓝天白云 畅行无阻 还有迎面而来的维他肥的味道
Blue skies, no air traffic, and that tangy scent of Vita-minamulch.
嗯
Mmm.
妈妈就是这样喷洒
Just like Momma used to spray.
真是享受
Delicious.
人老了嗅觉真的是最先退化的
They say the sense of smell is the first thing to go.
- 你闻到了吗?  - 该下班了!
- You smell it?  - Quitting time!
喷粉机去参加什么比赛
A crop duster wanting to be a racer.
要我说 参赛的飞机更想来当喷粉机呢
If you ask me, more racers should want to be crop dusters.
我补充了维他肥 耶! 维他肥
I got some minamulch, yeah! Minamulch
欢迎来到 普罗普沃什镇
嗯 现在有什么大豆汽油 柳枝汽油 海藻汽油 算了吧!
Yuck. Nowadays, they got soybean fuel, switchgrass fuel, algae fuel. Come on!
- 哦 都不健康! 别加那些油  - 快给我讲讲
- Oh, healthy! No tank you.  - Tell me about it.
- 接下来会是什么 开心果汽油?  - 你疯了吗?
- What's next, pistachio propane?  - What, are you nuts?
我只会买老牌的玉米汽油
For my money, there's nothing like good old-fashioned corn fuel.
- 哦 你说得没错  - 我都想好标语了
- Oh, yeah, you betcha.  - I even made up a slogan.
哦 我喜欢标语
Oh, slogans are good.
"玉米 你的能量之源"
"Corn. it gives you gas."
朗朗上口 我喜欢
Catchy. I like that.
我也喜欢 好了 斯帕奇 你的油加好了
Me, too. There you go, Sparky, you're all set.
- 待会见 楚格  - 好的
- Catch you later, Chug.  - Sure thing.
农田守望者达斯迪 呼叫楚格 完毕
This is Dusty Crophopper to Chug. Over.
这儿没有楚格 拜托 用新呼号
Uh, Chug isn't here. Come on, use the new call sign.
哦 对 对
Right, right, right.
中流砥柱 呃 呼叫超级教练大卡奇拉
This is, uh, Strut Jetstream calling Turbo Coach Truck-zilla.
- 准备好去训练了吗?  - 那还用说 砥柱
- Ready for practice?  - You betcha, Strut.
哈哈! 哇!
Ha-ha! Whoo!
小混蛋
Young punk.
好了 哥们 我看到你了
All right, buddy, I got you in sight.
我们先在玉米地里短途飞行热热身
Now let's start with some corn-row sprints.
来个20米低空飞行!
Drop and give me 20!
加油 哥们 保持住!
Come on, buddy, keep it going!
- 哦 华丽的转弯  - 下个项目是什么?
- Ooh, nice turn.  - What else you got?
现在我们练习一下树桩技巧
Okay. Now, let's try some treeline moguls.
好的!
Yeah!
一路上下俯冲
All the way up and down.
别摔着了
Don't be dogging it.
- 这就对了  - 哦 耶!
- That's how you do it.  - Ooh, yeah!
- 表现不错!  - 哈哈
- Looking good!  - Uh-huh.
接下来用你的佛衣调整倾斜角!
Okay, adjust your angle of bank with your alien irons!
飞行竞速初学者手册
- 你说的是"副翼"吗?  - 哦 是的
- You mean "ailerons"?  - Oh, yeah.
这样好了
Oh, great.
楚格和多蒂飞机加油站
输油管道及油冷却器没事
Oil lines and oil cooler check out.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
- AN八件套也没问题  - 太好了
- AN-8 fittings look fine.  - Nice.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你的主轴承油封坏了
You've worn out your main oil-seal.
啊 是吗?
Huh. Really?
这种损坏通常是由极高速度飞行造成的
That kind of damage comes from extremely high speeds.
嘿!
Hey!
将引擎加速到警戒线以上时间过长
Pushing the engine to the red line for prolonged periods of time.
- 那样做不太明智  - 没理由发生在身上
- That would be unwise.  - But that's not you.
你只是一架作物喷粉机 喷粉时
You're a crop duster and all you do is just dust crops
- 飞行速度很慢  - 嗯 飞得又慢又低
- at very low speeds.  - Yep, low and slow.
除非你又想去比赛了!
Unless you've been racing again!
不! 就我这样? 不可能
No! What, me? No.
达斯迪 你真是太棒了
Oh, man, Duster, you were in the zone,
土星火箭也追不上你
where a Saturn rocket couldn't catch you!
发射!
Ballistic!
你就是光速 光速!
We're talking light speed. Light speed, here!
这周末的资格赛你一定能成功的
You're going to tear it up at the qualifier this weekend.
耶... 哦 棒极了
Yea... Oh, Shelby.
呃... 我不知道他在说什么
Um... I don't know.
达斯迪 你不能比赛
Dusty, you're not built to race.
你是给农作物喷粉的
You're built to dust crops.
你知不知道肆意妄为的后果是什么?
Do you know what will happen if you push it too far?
机翼颤抖 金属疲劳 最后引擎失灵
Wing flutter, metal fatigue, turbine failure.
- 引擎失灵?  - 哦 不 我要掉下去了!
- Turbine failure?  - Oh, no, I'm going down!
我为什么没听多蒂的话?
Why didn't I listen to Dottie?
是啊 你为什么不听多蒂的话?
Yeah, why don't you listen to Dottie?
她是这世界上最明智的机械师!
She's the smartest mechanic in the world!
- 哦 天啊!  - 怎么了?
- Oh, my gosh!  - What?
- 孤儿院!  - 不
- The orphanage!  - No.
- 不要撞到孤儿院!  - 孩子们 快跑!
- Not the orphanage!  - Kids, out of the way!
嘣!
Kaboom!
孩子们!
The kids!
哇! 真是生动形象的表演
Wow! That was vivid and specific.
所以我才希望你和我们一起去资格赛
And exactly why I need you to come with us to the qualifier.
难以置信
You're unbelievable.
听到了吗? 他说我难以置信
Oh. Did you hear that? I'm unbelievable.
可怜的孤儿们!
The orphans!
欢迎观看本期节目 两周后环球之翼比赛即将开始
Tune in, in two weeks for the start of the Wings Around the Globe.
知道吗 这次该我们大显身手了 兄弟
You know, I think we've got a really good shot at this, buddy.
是啊! 希望那时我能看完这本书
Oh, yeah! Especially if I finish this book by then.
哦! 这个节目我喜欢!
Oh! I love this show!
史上最壮烈的10次坠落!
The 10 best air crashes of all time!
- 哇! 啊  - 坏了
- Whoa! Oh.  - Not good.
怎么会这样?
How does that happen?
这些可没什么帮助
That is not going to buff out.
或许这里没有收录比赛可能遇到的所有情况
You know, this might not cover everything you could run into out there.
- 那你说还有什么?  - 不知道
- What are you getting at?  - I don't know.
我在想 我们是不是得找个人帮忙
I'm just wondering if maybe we need, uh, some help.
帮忙? 找谁?
Help? From who?
哦 比如斯基珀
Oh, well, like the Skipper.
就是那个破旧的"海盗"号
That old Corsair down at the end of the runway?
- 没错 他是个战争英雄  - 就他那老身子骨
- Sure, he's a war hero.  - He's an old crankshaft.
我哥们斯帕奇说
My buddy, Sparky, says the Skipper
斯基珀曾是海军传奇教员
was a legendary flight instructor in the navy.
没错 他精通一切
That's right. He knows stuff.
他已经十几年没飞行了
He's been grounded for decades.
我为什么要请一个不再飞行的飞机当我的教练?
Why would I want to be coached by a plane who doesn't even fly?
最起码他是个飞机啊
At least he's a plane.
史上最壮烈的坠落第一...
The number one crash of all time...
哦 天啊!
Oh, man!
我没事
I'm okay.
哦! 肯定很疼
Ooh! That's got to hurt.
据说他击落了50架飞机
They say he shot down 50 planes.
我听过很多他们乔利扳手中队的故事
I heard stories about his squadron, the Jolly Wrenches.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
他们是海军里最凶猛强悍的飞行中队
They were the roughest, toughest, meanest flyers in the navy.
杀人不眨眼
Ruthless killers who showed no mercy.
- 等一下...  - 不眨眼!
- Uh, wait, so...  - No mercy!
只要他们看到你 就会向你射击
They would shoot you as soon as look at you.
希望你准备好了
I hope you're right about this.
楚格!
Chug!
我在这里等你
I'll wait here.
嗯...
Uh...
你好 斯基珀
Hey, there, Skipper.
是这样的 我正在准备环球之翼飞行大赛
Say, I'm trying out for the Wings Around the Globe Rally.
我知道你不能再飞了
And I know you can't fly anymore,
但有句话叫"不能做的飞机可以当老师"
but, you know, they say, "Those who can't do, teach."
所以...
So...
我是想说 你比卡车要强得多了
Okay, what I mean to say is, you're not a truck.
所以你能不能指导我一下?
So, I was wondering if you would train me?
再接再厉 他接纳你了
Go on, he's warming up to you.
听说你曾击落了50架飞机
So, I heard you shot down 50 planes.
你想成为第51架?
You looking to be number 51?
呃... 不想
Uh... No.
别这样! 等一下
No, no, no! Wait, wait.
我想... 以我的头脑加上你的经验...
I just... I figured, with my guts and your glory...
要是不想你的头脑变成润滑油被涂在跑道上
Your guts would be a grease spot on a runway somewhere.
赶紧回家吧 别想那些不实际的 孩子
Go home. You're in over your head, kid.
你曾飞行过那么多...
Look, you flew all those...
我们去后门再试试
Let's try the back door.
内布拉斯加州 林肯市
- 早上好 林肯市!  - 嘿 达斯迪!
- Hello, Lincoln!  - Hey, Dusty!
真不知道我为什么要跟你们一块来
I don't know how you talked me into coming to this.
来吧 多蒂
Now, come on, Dottie.
哇! 难以置信 那是红尾野马!
Wow! I don't believe it. A Red Tail P-51!
哦 天啊! 是海怒!
Oh, man! A Sea Fury!
快看啊!
Check it out!
哇!
Wow!
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentleplanes.
请大家注意了
May we have your attention, please?
请将您的挡风玻璃朝向天空
Kindly direct your windscreens to the heavens above
热烈欢迎我们的特别来宾
and give a warm welcome to our special guest.
螺旋桨王子
The Prince of Propellers.
一直被模仿
When he's speeding, he's leading.
快把我英俊的侧影照下来
Get my good side, fellas.
却从未被超越
When he's grinning, he's winning.
有请独一无二的
The one and only
里普斯林杰!
Ripslinger!
你们被我的拉烟包围啦
You're caught in the riptide!
欢迎你的到来
Thanks for coming out.
谁想照相? 好的 一个一个来
Who wants a picture? All right, one at a time.
除了那些自我吹嘘 他还是很谦虚的嘛
Well, with all that self-promotion, at least he's modest.
多蒂 那可是里普斯林杰
Dottie, that's Ripslinger.
他是RPX飞行队的队长 人们叫他...
He's captain of Team RPX. They call him...
绿色风暴
The Green Tornado.
他太棒了 直接晋级
Oh, he's so good, he's pre-qualified.
哦 这两位是内德和扎德
Oh. And those two, Ned and Zed.
涡轮两兄弟
The Twin Turbos.
他们是世界级选手
They're world-class racers.
知道吗 据说他们曾是一架飞机 出生的时候分裂成了两架
You know, I hear they used to be one plane and were separated at birth.
哇 真希望我出生的时候也分裂成两辆车
Wow. I wish I was separated at birth.
观众们...
Okay, people...
今天是四场预选赛中的最后一站
this is the last of four time trials being held worldwide.
今天的比赛项目是围绕桥塔飞行
Today's qualifying round is one lap around the pylons.
成绩最好五架飞机有资格晋级环球之翼
The top five finishers will qualify for the Wings Around the Globe Rally.
拭目以待吧
Oh, yeah.
弗扎雷利 该你上场了
Fonzarelli, you're up, my man.
哦 真是恶心
Oh, man! That's nasty.
他飞过了起飞线!
And he's through the start gate!
参赛飞机必须水平飞过蓝色桥塔
The racers must pass through the blue pylons on the horizontal
然后垂直从红色桥塔之间穿过
and around the red pylons on the knife-edge.
他到了三号门!
Now he's coming back to Gate Three!
飞得漂亮 兄弟
Nicely done, my man.
他在这个蓝色桥塔飞得比较高
Setting himself up a little high through the blue pylons there,
是在为前面的方阵做准备
lining up for the quadro.
他以一个高难度270度的大转弯完成了右转! 太棒了!
He's taking a hard right with a 270-degree high-G turn! Yeah!
他飞回来了 哇!
Back all the way around. Whoo!
- 顺利通过 哈! 太棒了 兄弟!  - 他真厉害
- Cleanly through. Ha! Look at you, man!  - That guy's good.
无懈可击的动作 速度很快
It doesn't get much better than that. All right. Good speed.
接下来是三塔阵 需要极强的倾斜控制力
Lining up for the three-pylon chicane, amazing pitch control.
流畅! 迅速! 轻松通过!
Smooth! Fast! Clean!
他来到了最后一轮
He's going into the final turn,
垂直8字动作 至少需要9.2倍过载的转向
into the half-Cuban 8, pulling an aggressive 9.2 Gs.
他开始爬升了!
Attacking the climb!
哇 速度真快
Wow. Now that's some speed.
观众们 他完美地完成垂直8字动作
Coming out of the Cuban 8 at the end of a fantastic first run, people.
成绩是1分24秒16
A 01.24.16.
其他对手想要超越可很难啊
A very good time for the other racers to try and beat.
他快速穿过了红色桥塔
Fast, tight through the pylons.
表现得不错
He's got a great pace going, here.
他只落后了半秒
He's just a half a second behind.
- 哦! 引擎失灵!  - 哦!
- Oh! Engine failure!  - Oh!
你的比赛结束 拜拜
Out of the race. Bye-bye.
表现得不错 不过注意时间
Great performance. Watch the clock here.
我都着急了 接下来是蓝色大门
I can't wait. Lining up for the Blue Gate.
哦 不 他没做好! 这要被罚分的
Oh, no, he did not! That's a major penalty.
- 不好意思了 兄弟  - 第八位
- Sorry, dude.  - Eighth place.
速度真快
Talk about fast.
完成了垂直8字
Coming out the Cuban 8.
整装待发 兄弟
Fueled and ready, man.
好了 该你了
Okay, bud, you're up.
一切就绪
Good and tight.
- 都准备好了  - 今天的比赛十分精彩
- All set.  - It's been a wonderful day here,
还有最后一位参赛者
and we're down to our last competitor.
该走了
This is it.
来自普罗普沃什镇的中流·砥柱
From Propwash Junction, Strut Jetstream.
"中流砥柱"?
"Strut Jetstream"?
是哦 史上最酷的呼号 我想出来的
Yep. Awesomest call sign ever. It was my idea.
- 好吧 怪不得  - 嘿 农业机!
- Ah. That explains it.  - Hey, ag-plane!
园艺活昨天就收工了 伙计 离开跑道 我们正比赛呢
Landscaping was yesterday, man. Get off the runway. We're racing, here.
- 再次呼叫中流·砥柱  - 不 不 停!
- Second call for Strut Jetstream.  - No, no, no!
- 我们在找...  - 是的! 我就是中流砥柱
- Looking for...  - Yo! I'm Strut Jetstream.
- 你是中流砥柱?  - 是的
- You are Strut Jetstream?  - Yep.
作物喷粉机? 哥们 这到底是怎么回事?
A crop duster? Man, what's going on here?
是个飞机就能比赛吗?
Is everybody getting to fly today?
哥们 你妈妈真是望子成龙啊
Man, your momma must have had high hopes for you.
听着 你知道你生来是为了庄稼的 不是来拼速度的
Now, you know you are built for seed, not speed.
开什么玩笑
You have got to be kidding me.
那个乡巴佬也要来参赛?
That farmer's going to race?
说真的 就凭这么小的螺旋桨?
Seriously, with a prop that small?
他可能是和旁边那辆漏油的
Maybe he races that leaky,
破旧的老卡车比赛吧
old fuel truck next to him.
说谁漏油呢?
Who are you calling leaky?
话这么多嘴干不 我漏点给你洗嘴巴
I'll leak on you, if you don't check your intake.
别和他们一般见识
Don't lower yourself to their level.
加油啊 达斯... 加油 砥柱
Go on Dus... Go on, Strut.
那家伙是谁?
Who's that guy?
- 你还真打算试试?  - 作物喷粉机?
- You're going to try out?  - A crop duster?
玉米地在那边
Cornfield is over that way.
请了天假就为了尝尝失败的滋味!
Nice of you to take the day off just to lose!
去吧 达斯迪!
Go, Duster!
想把弗扎雷利从第五挤下来简直是天方夜谭
It's going to be a tall order for him to knock Fonzarelli out of fifth place.
他起飞啦!
And he's off!
好吧 开始飞得还有所保留
Well, he's starting a little conservative.
有点看头
This ought to be rich.
时速193英里
193 miles per hour.
他来到了2号门 稳稳地平飞通过
He's into Gate Two, clean through the horizontal.
搞什么? 他还真能割草啊
What? He's practically mowing the lawn.
帮我修修草坪吧 哥们
Come to my house, man.
好的 第一节结束 他落后弗扎雷利整整一秒钟
Okay. At the first split, he's a full second behind Fonzarelli.
是的 差了不少时间 不过这家伙还挺有闯劲的
Yo, that's a lot of time to make up, but this guy's aggressive.
现在他在在做高难度270度大转弯
Now he's making that hard 270-degree high-G turn!
哇! 做的好!
Whoo! That's it!
准备好了 垂直左转
Setting himself up. Left vertical turn.
对准3塔阵
Lining up for the three-pylon chicane.
他在加速
He's gaining speed.
现在 他只落后弗扎雷利半秒钟了
Now, he's only half a second behind Fonzarelli.
快要赶上了
And he is closing rapidly.
他回到双塔 向上升！又高又陡!
Now he's back on that stick. Up he goes! Up and away!
只差弗扎雷利0.2秒了!
Now only two-tenths of a second behind Fonzarelli!
- 加油 达斯迪!  - 噢 就要结束了
- Come on, Duster!  - Oh, it's going to be close.
他能做到的 他行的
He's going to do it. He's going to do it.
噢 好样的! 完美的着陆 这才叫飞行!
Oh, yes! What a finish! Now, that's what you call flying!
做的好 达斯迪
Way to go, Dustmeister.
我早就知道你行的
That's what I'm talking about.
中流的成绩是
Jetstream, the official time is
1分24秒26
1 minute, 24.26 seconds.
第六名 就差一点点 真可惜
Sixth place, but what a close one, people.
好了 伙计们 环球之翼飞行大赛资格赛结束了
Well, folks, that wraps up the trials for the Wings Around the Globe Rally.
嘿 伙计 第六名不丢人
Hey, pal, sixth place ain't nothing to be ashamed of.
你飞得真不赖
That was a heck of a run.
谢谢
Thanks.
哇! 戴格! 让我来开!
Ow! Dagnabbit! Let me drive!
好啦 大功告成 救火车
There you go, topped off and all set, Mayday.
你能不能停下来! 难以置信!
Will you stop! Unbelievable!
你要不要重跑一趟!
Why don't you just go back!
你有一个坑没压到!
I mean, I think you actually missed a pothole!
哥们 你是史上最糟糕
Man, you got to be the worst,
最糟糕的送快递的运货车!
I mean the worst delivery truck that has ever delivered a delivery!
有什么能为你效劳的?
Can I help you?
告诉我这里一定是普罗普沃什镇吧
Please tell me this is Propwash Junction.
没错
Sure is.
终于到了 地图上都找不到这
Oh, finally. You know, you're not even on the map.
是啊 旅途还挺愉快 对吗?
Yeah, pretty drive though, ain't it?
噢 当然 要是我喜欢灰尘和玉米就更完美了
Oh, yeah. Especially if you like looking at dirt and corn.
不提了 我来找中流·砥柱
Anyway, I'm looking for a Strut Jetstream.
- 谁?  - 中流 我找中流·砥柱
- Who?  - Jetstream. Strut Jetstream.
不认识 想不起来有这号人 你有照片吗?
Nope, doesn't ring a bell. Do you have a photo?
是的 在这呢 没有 我没照片!
Yeah, I got one right here. No, I don't have a photo!
文件上写着
I have documentation that says
中流·砥柱住在普罗普沃什镇
Strut Jetstream lives in Propwash Junction.
噢 哇 哇! 哇 等等! 好的! 噢...
Oh, whoa, whoa! Whoa, wait a minute! Okay! Oh...
不 天啊 我...
No, gosh I...
嘿 我就是中流砥柱
Hey, I'm Strut Jetstream.
是啊! 我就说！
Yeah! That's right!
我就知道我记得 就是他 在那溜达呢
I knew I'd remember. There he is, strutting on over here.
不过你发音有点不标准
But you're mispronouncing it slightly.
- 是吗?  - 嗯 是的
- I am?  - Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
实际上应该是 "农田守望者达斯迪"
It's actually pronounced "Dusty Crophopper."
农田守望者达斯迪
Dusty Crophopper.
没错 是个斯堪的纳维亚名字
Yeah. It's Scandinavian.
没错 我是埃及人
Right, and I'm Egyptian.
我的天啊! 一股什么味?
Googly moogly! What is that smell?
- 是维它肥  - 维他命什么?
- It's Vita-minamulch.  - Vita-mina-what?
密西西比这边最香的农家肥
The finest-smelling compost this side of the Mississippi.
天然的 奶油状 很厚重的感觉
Original, creamy and chunky style.
噢 没错 闻到了吗? 像是水仙花
Oh, yeah. Smell that? It's like daffodils
就和周末大餐一样 我爱死它了 我就爱这味道
and like Sunday dinner. I just love it. I love it.
维它肥 太棒了! 维它肥 太棒了!
I got some minamulch, yeah! I got some minamulch, yeah!
这老飞机脑子有病 这你们都知道吗?
That old airplane needs some help. Y'all know that, right?
知道
Yeah.
你们知道赛用燃料添加剂硝基甲烷吗?
Are you familiar with the racing fuel additive, nitro methane?
噢 是的! 活力果汁! 可带劲了!
Oh, yeah! Zip juice! Go-go punch!
那玩意会模糊视线 速度加快
That stuff will blur your vision and slur your speech.
- 是违禁品  - 严禁使用
- It's illegal.  - Totally illegal.
都不知道长啥样 好的 你说什么?
Wouldn't know what it looks like. Yeah, you were saying?
我们弗扎雷利的油箱里发现了此种成分
That substance was found in the tank of the fifth-place qualifier, Fonzarelli.
使用违禁品会被自动取消资格
Illegal fuel intake is an automatic DQ.
等等 你的意思是...
Wait, so you're saying...
他被淘汰了 你入选了 祝贺你
He's out, you're in. Congratulations.
- 你入选了?  - 嗯
- You're in?  - Hmm.
他入选啦!
He's in!
你信吗 他入选了!
You're never going to believe this. He's in!
达斯迪要参加比赛啦! 多蒂 他入选啦！
Dusty's in the race! Dottie, he's in!
什么? 逗我玩呢?
What? Are you serious?
哇! 达斯迪
Whoo! Dusty.
悠着点哦 安全第一
Don't do anything crazy. Fly safe.
老兄 这实在太酷了
Man, it's going to be cool.
你要飞过几万英里宽的海洋
You're going to cross oceans thousands of miles wide.
可能会冻坏你的方向舵...
Freezing your rudder off one day...
- 也许会烧掉它  - 还有变态的飓风
- And burning it off the next!  - Freaking hurricanes.
- 旋风!  - 台风!
- Cyclones!  - Typhoons!
- 季风！  - 龙卷风！
- Monsoons!  - Tornadoes!
- 沙尘暴!  - 风雨交加!
- Sandstorms!  - Gale force winds!
没错!
Yeah!
嗯
Hmm.
坏主意
Bad idea.
你会冒着烟坠落在山边
You'll end up a smoking hole on the side of a mountain
零件分别掉在五个国家
with your parts spread over five countries.
你凭什么这么说?
What makes you say that?
你将要和世界上最厉害的选手竞争
You're going up against the best racers in the world.
这些人有些都跑不完全程
And some of them don't even finish.
你横滚时粗心大意的
You're sloppy on your rolls,
转弯太大 直行太慢
wide on your turns, slow on your straightaways.
你看了我的比赛?
You've been watching me?
是啊 瞧你像个傻瓜一样犯错
Yeah, watching you make a fool out of yourself.
垂直穿门时应该更果断
You need to be tighter getting in and out of your knife-edge.
好的
Okay.
任何多余的控制都会让你减速
Any extra control input costs you speed and seconds.
- 所以 你觉得我有点过了?  - 没错 菜鸟常犯的错
- So, you think I'm overcorrecting?  - Absolutely. Rookie mistake.
你是在提点我吗?
Are you giving me pointers?
不是! 我是在劝你清醒点 别痴心妄想了
No! I'm telling you to forget all this racing malarkey.
你天生就不合适 你是个作物喷粉机！
You just ain't built for it. You're a crop duster!
你以为我自己不知道吗?
You don't think I know that?
我才是那个整天在同一块地
I'm the one who's been flying back and forth
飞来飞去的人 日复一日 年复一年!
across the same fields day after day, month after month, for years!
我已经飞了近万英里
I have flown thousands of miles
可我哪都没去过
and I have never been anywhere.
不像你
Not like you.
你为战斗而生 瞧瞧你的成就!
You were built to fight, and look what you did!
你是个英雄
You're a hero.
我只是想去证明也许 只是也许
I'm just trying to prove that maybe, just maybe,
我能突破自我 做点不一样的事
I can do more than what I was built for.
你知道吗? 忘了我的话吧
You know what? Just forget it.
你永远不会懂的
You'll never understand.
明天早上 0500 别迟到了
0500, tomorrow. Don't be late.
等等 0500?
Wait. 0500?
没错 早上5点
Yeah, 5:00 a.m.
斯帕奇 望远镜
Sparky, binoculars.
这可是精密光学仪器啊
Those are some mighty clean optics, there.
你用的什么? 一种鹿皮?
What do you use? Some kind of shammy?
- 噢 不是 这是一种特殊的微纤维布  - 哈 微纤维
- Oh, no, it's a special microfiber cloth.  - Ah. Microfiber.
没错 不含棉绒 无划痕 回头我给你也弄点
Yeah, lint-free, scratch-free. I'll get you some.
我认识个海军退役哥们 他按批发价卖给我
I got an ex-Navy buddy who sells them to me wholesale.
我帮他做个网站...
I helped him set up his web...
别说了 我们还有很多事要做
Knock it off. We got a lot of work to do.
- 回头介绍你认识  - 谢谢
- I'll hook you up.  - Thanks.
好啦 达斯迪 记住
All right, Dusty, remember this.
重点不是你飞得有多快 而是你如何快速飞
It ain't how fast you fly, it's how you fly fast.
- 记住了  - 让我看看你有什么能耐
- Roger that.  - Show me what you got.
瞧好吧! 噢 耶
Watch this! Oh, yeah.
还不错 你能高低来回飞 还有什么?
Great, you can go up and down. What else?
- 让我看看你的转弯  - 来了!
- Show me your turns.  - Here we go!
你觉得这就不错了? 烂透了! 垂直穿越那些榆树
You think that was good? That stunk! Knife-edge those elm trees.
噢 加油 头抬高点!
Oh, come on. Keep your nose up!
嘿 斯基
Hey, Skip.
- 你想要速度 对吗?  - 是的
- You want speed, right?  - Yeah.
- 说真的 闪电那么快?  - 噢 没错!
- Serious, bolt-rattling speed?  - Oh, yeah!
向上看 看到那些云了吗?
Then look up. Do you see those clouds?
空中高速公路
The highway in the sky.
逐风而行是无可比拟的体验
Tailwinds like nothing you've ever flown.
还在等什么?
What are you waiting for?
来吧 火力全开 相信自己
Come on, power up. Firewall thrust.
最大扭矩 最大!
Max torque, max torque!
好的 看上去还不错
All right, looking good.
保持好位置 达斯迪 最大速度
Hold V-Y, Dusty. Max rate, now.
头抬太高了 低一点
Your nose is too high. Get your nose down.
你会失速的 减少倾斜度 低点！
You're going to stall. Ease off the pitch. Nose down!
噢！
Oh!
嘿 你在搞什么?
Hey, what are you doing?
刚刚在上面怎么了?
What just happened up there?
我... 我燃料不足了
I'm... I'm low on fuel.
我看起来像昨天才出厂吗?
Do I look like I was built yesterday?
- 不 不 说来话长  - 我有空
- No, no. It's a long story.  - I got time.
额...
Uh...
好的 这么说 你知道
Okay, well, um, you know,
我觉得 我的轴流式压缩机有些问题 所以...
I feel like I was having some problems with my axial compressor so...
在乔利扳手有句名言 Volo Pro Veritas
The Jolly Wrenches have a motto, Volo Pro Veritas.
意思是 "为真理而飞行"
It means "I fly for truth."
很明显 你不是
Clearly, you don't.
斯帕奇 推我回机库
Sparky, push me back to the hangar.
我恐高
I'm afraid of heights.
- 你是飞机啊  - 我是作物喷粉机
- But you're a plane.  - I'm a crop duster.
我从没飞过高于一千尺
I've never flown over a thousand feet.
开什么玩笑?
Are you kidding?
恐高还想环游世界比赛?
Scared of heights and you want to race around the world?
额 斯基 图洪加海港受袭那次
Uh, Skip, during the attack of Tujunga Harbor,
就连那些P-38都有点恐高
why, even the P-38s had trouble at high altitudes.
听着 他们又不用飞跃喜马拉雅山 对吗?
Well, they didn't have to fly over the Himalayas, did they?
我还是会贴着地 就高一点点
I'll still be low to the ground, just high up.
战争结束后 那些P-38拿了冠军
And after the war, those 38s went on to win races.
真的吗? 是真的吗?
Really? Is that true?
是的 真人真事 好像是第46届克利夫兰比赛
Yeah, true. Like in the Cleveland race of '46.
- 真的?  - 等等 还不止呢
- For real?  - Wait, it gets better.
在第49届比赛 空中骑士P-38战机平均时速337英里
In '49, the P-38 Sky Ranger averaged 337 miles per hour.
等等 337?
Wait, 337?
好吧 实际上是337.4 但记录册里四舍五入了
Well, actually 337.4, but they round it down in the record books.
你怎么记得这么清楚?
Why would you do that?
有些人对小数毫不在乎
Some people just have no respect for decimal points.
- 是的 我知道 和我说说  - 为什么他们就不能向上取整呢?
- Yeah, I know. Tell me about it.  - Why couldn't they round it up?
- 说真的 他...  - 好啦 好啦
- Seriously, he...  - All right, all right.
这么说 你喜欢低空飞行 我们想想怎么办
So, you're a flat-hatter. We'll work on that.
想想有没有办法把又低又慢 变成又低又快
But for now let's see if we can turn low and sloppy into low and fast.
收到
Roger that.
这样吧
It'll go like this.
旗帜那是起跑线
The flag marks the start line.
玉米地那头 有三个粮仓
Across the cornfield, three silos are waiting for you.
利用径向过载飞过那些障碍
Slalom those with a radial-G pass.
等等 "径向" 什么载?
Wait. "A radial" what pass?
一旦越过树木
Once you get to the trees,
调到最佳速度 保持飞行高度500英尺
go to your optimal rate of climb to about 500 feet.
倒飞再横滚回来 用高度换速度
Roll inverted and extend, trading altitude for air speed
- 然后俯冲至终点  - 嗯 好的
- and dive toward the finish line.  - Uh, okay.
照我说的做 就有机会打败他
You string all that together, you might have a chance to beat him.
我和谁比赛?
Who am I racing?
他来了
Here he comes.
他是个双发通勤机 大概1500马力
He's a twin commuter pushing about 1500 horsepower.
额 他飞得太高了
Uh, he's pretty high up.
不是和他比 和他的影子比赛
You're not racing him, you're racing his shadow.
到水塔前打败他
Beat it to the water tower.
开始吧！绕过粮仓!
Let's do this! Thread the silos!
跟紧！转弯时再斜点
Tighter! Lean into your turns more.
- 他转的真烂  - 没错
- His turns are terrible.  - Yeah.
加油啊 达斯迪 快点
Let's go, Dusty. Faster.
你落后了
You're falling behind.
开始爬升 在俯冲时追上他
Begin your climb and catch him in the dive.
开始俯冲
Start your dive now.
算了 你已经输了
Never mind, you already lost.
我们可以提升动力或者减少阻力
So, we can increase power or we can decrease drag.
当然是增加动力
Definitely increase power.
更大的扭矩意味着更快的速度
More torque means more speed.
太次了
Lousy.
试着利用径向过载
Come on, let's work that radial-G turn.
再做一次 再来 再来
Do it again. One more time. Again!
加油! 达斯迪
Come on! Push it, Dusty!
有进步!
Better!
记住 高度换速度
Remember now, altitude for airspeed.
重力是你的好帮手
Gravity is your ally.
物理定律支配着速度
The laws of physics govern speed.
达斯迪 尽你所能吧
All right, Dusty. Give this run all you've got.
利用你的径向过载
Use your radial-G.
让重力为你而战
Let gravity work for you.
看起来不错 这就是我所说的
Looking good. That's what I'm talking about.
让仪表盘烧起来吧! 冲啊!
Firewall the throttle! Go! Go! Go!
干的好! 达斯迪
You got it, Duster!
开始攀升!
Begin your climb!
高度换速度
All right, altitude for airspeed.
在俯冲的时候追上他!
Catch him in the dive!
开始俯冲!
Dive now!
像子弹一样!
Ballistic!
他超过阿斯顿马丁了!
He kicked Aston Martins out there!
- 达斯迪真汉子!  - 他已经准备好了
- Dusterino!  - He's ready.
- 喔!  - 太帅了
- Whoa!  - Oh, that's cool.
活塞和交叉的扳手 你的中队标志
The piston and cross-wrenches. Your squadron insignia.
- 这是你努力的结果  - 很适合你
- You've earned it.  - It fits you.
- 太适合你了 达斯迪  - 听着
- It fits you, Dusty.  - Now, listen.
比赛开始时所有的飞机起飞
When the race starts and all those planes take off,
会引起一阵强大的涡流
it'll stir up a bunch of swirlies
扳手中队在航空线之争战役中遇到过
just like the Wrenches ran into in the Battle of Airway.
明白 真希望你能和我一起去 斯基
Roger that. Sure wish you were coming with me, Skip.
到检查点后跟我无线电联系
Just radio back when you get to the check points.
我会在这做你的僚机
I'll be your wingman from here.
为真理而飞行 对吧
Volo Pro Veritas, right?
为真理而飞行
Volo Pro Veritas.
- 让他们见识一下 兄弟  - 我们都为你骄傲
- Kick some tail, buddy.  - We're all proud of you.
喔! 达斯迪先生!
Whoo-hoo! Dustmeister!
喔
Wow.
呼叫 呼叫
Break, break.
7号参赛机 7号参赛机
Air racer number 7, Air racer number 7.
是否收到? 这里是肯尼迪入场管制 完毕
Do you read? Kennedy approach, over.
我是农田守望者达斯迪 我在寻找JFK机场
I'm Dusty Crophopper, I'm looking for JFK airport.
农田守望者7号 你不应该脱离塔台的视线
Crophopper 7, you are supposed to be on the Carnice visual.
左转 航向1-9-5
Turn further left, heading 1-9-5.
保持高度1000 接收22号跑道导航信标
Maintain 1,000 feet. Intercept the 22 right localizer.
22号跑道空闲 尽快进场
You are cleared for the ILS 22, right approach.
- 收到  - 你后方有大型飞机
- Roger.  - Heavy is sectored in behind you.
请再重复一遍
Run that by me one more time.
左转 航向1-9-5 保持高度1000...
Turn further left, heading 1-9-5. Maintain 1,000...
好的 明白了
Never mind. I got it.
你看到他了吗?
Do you see him?
雷达有显示 但我连影都没见着
Well, radar does, but I don't see diddly.
看看这跑道! 太棒了! 这么光滑
Check out this pavement! Nice! It's so smooth.
农田守望者7号 你错过了F滑行道 向左去C滑行道
Crophopper 7, you passed Foxtrot. Turn left onto Charlie.
别在22号跑道待太久
Hold short at 22.
等等 我以为
Wait, I thought...
- 快离开跑道!  - 哇!
- Get off the runway!  - Whoa!
- 不好意思  - 回泽西岛去吧 废柴
- Oh. Sorry.  - Go back to Jersey, you bum.
不好意思 我在哪能...
Excuse me, where can I...
能看着点吗? 我在工作
Hey-ho, do you mind? I'm working here.
对不起
Sorry.
他是个好人 但是太轻浮了 你懂得
A nice enough guy, but way too much baggage, if you know what I mean.
你好 我想去匹兹营地
Oh, hey, there. I'm looking for pit row.
匹兹? 简单
The pits? Oh, yeah, that's easy.
你从这条路一直走到消防站
You want to go down this way toward the fire station.
A滑行道有个朝左的路口
Then taxiway alpha forks off to the left.
但是别走那条路 你应该向右转
But don't go that way. You want to veer right.
如果到了橙色的筒 你就走过了 所以...
And if you get to the orange barrels, you went too far. So...
就一直往前走然后右转
Just go straight ahead and to the right.
好的 谢了 漆喷的不错
Great, thanks. Hey, nice paint job.
多谢夸奖 我也为此而自豪
Well, thank you! I'm kind of proud of it.
- 我觉得他说的是我  - 好吧
- I think he was talking to me.  - Oh.
看看这是谁 斯堪的纳维亚人
Well, looky who's here. The Scandinavian.
- 呃...  - 想家吗?
- Hey. Uh...  - Miss your home town?
我就不想 刚刚这个想法抛到九霄云外了
I don't. Just about blocked that memory out of my mind.
但是你的味道又把它带回来了...
But you're bringing it right back with that...
噢 你怎么还是这股臭烘烘的维它什么肥的味道啊
Oh, man, that nasty Vita-mina-stink-a-bunch.
你的帐篷是左边的最后一个 快去吧!
Your tent's the last one on the left. Go!
好嘞
Okay.
澡堂在右边 随便说说
Power wash is on the right. Just saying.
喔! 从欧洲杯脱颖而出的牛头犬? 大狗!
Wow! Bulldog? From the European Cup? The Big Dog!
我看到过你做那不可思议的高过载垂直转弯
Hey, I saw you do this unbelievable high-G vertical turn.
你怎么做到的?
How did you do that?
竖起耳朵
Well, let me tell you.
我告诉你我所有的飞行秘密如何?
In fact, why don't I tell you all my racing secrets?
- 真的?  - 你说呢
- Really?  - No.
听着 我不知道
Look, I don't know how things work
你们那穷乡僻壤情况如何
in the backwater from which you hail, matey,
但这是场比赛
but this is a competition.
大家都各自为战! 拜拜
Every plane for himself! Goodbye.
是啊 当然了
Yeah, sure.
- 喔...啊!  - 唔
- Whoa... Whoa!  - Oh.
噢
Uh... Oh.
等等 这是玻光蜡100型号
Wait a second. This is AeroShell 100.
我记得我订的是DT-2380
I thought I ordered the DT-2380.
不好意思让你看到我出丑了
Well, I am sorry you had to see that.
- 你还好吧?  - 当然了 怎么会不好呢?
- Are you all right?  - Sure. Why wouldn't I be?
你是泛亚的冠军和蒙巴杯的记录保持者 伊莎妮
And you are Pan-Asian Champion and Mumbai Cup record holder, Ishani.
大家都叫我"伊莎妮"
Most people call me just "Ishani."
我是达斯迪 我是说我的名字是达斯迪
I'm Dusty. I mean, uh, my name is Dusty.
但我并不是真的满身灰尘 我很干净的
I'm not actually dusty, I'm quite clean.
幸会 "小干净"达斯迪
It's very nice to meet you, "quite clean" Dusty.
我也很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you, too.
看看那螺旋桨
Look at that propeller.
真棒
Ooh.
往那边一点 别太用力
A little over there. Not so much pressure, okay?
打扰一下 让一让
Oh, excuse me, guys. Pardon me.
就是这样
Yeah.
看看谁来了!
Hey, look who made it!
- 喷粉机  - 你好
- It's the crop duster.  - Hey.
你的到来是一个很有意思的故事
You know, having you here is a nice vehicle-interest story.
小镇农民来到这盛大的节日
Small-town farmer makes it to the big time.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
- 但起飞时不幸遭遇事故  - 什么?
- But tragically crashes on takeoff.  - What?
环球之翼大赛冠军里普斯林杰
Wings around The Globe winner, Ripslinger,
会称赞默默无闻的乡巴佬然后把他葬在玉米地里
eulogizes the unknown hayseed and scatters his debris over a cornfield.
人气肯定会暴增啊!
Ratings will be through the roof!
- 好吧  - 祝你好运
- Okay.  - Good luck.
- 土鳖  - 什么?
- Farm boy.  - What?
人民英雄驾到
The hero of the people has arrived.
你们从没听说过伟大的卓帕卡布拉?
You have never heard of the great El Chupacabra?
这不是那个专吸小车燃料的怪物吗?
Hey, isn't that that monster that siphons fuel from small vehicles?
不不 这只是为了让对手
No, no, no, it's just a stage name
感到恐惧而设计的噱头而已
designed to strike fear into the hearts of my opponents.
是啊 他是墨西哥室内比赛的冠军
Yeah, he's the indoor racing champion of all Mexico.
室内比赛?
Indoor racing?
我也是一个艺人 电视剧明星 浪漫小说家
And numero uno recording artist, telenovela star and romance novelist.
你刚才说卓帕卡布拉 还是碎嘴卡布拉?
Did you say El Chupacabra or El Cuckoo-cabra?
你嘲笑我? 你竟敢嘲笑我?
You make joke? You make joke?
很好 你让我别无选择!
Very well. You leave me no choice!
向你扇动我的披风!
I swish my cape at you!
你已经被羞辱了
You have been shamed.
哎呀 我好怕怕呀
I hope I can get over it.
吓死人咧!
Oh. I just did!
嘿 我去年看了机动电视台播出的你的比赛
Hey, I saw you race on Telemoto last year.
当然 那是在西班牙 所以我不是很了解
Of course, it was in Spanish, so I didn't understand everything.
受宠若惊 小飞机
I am flattered, avión peque?o.
你之前参加过很多这样的盛会了吧?
You have done many of these long distance rallies, yes?
- 没有 这是我第一次  - 我也是第一次
- No, this is my first one.  - It is my first time, as well!
我们俩会经历很多奇遇
We will have many adventures, you and I.
我们会笑 会哭 还会翩翩起舞
We will laugh, we will cry, we will dance!
呃...
Um... Wow.
- 当然不是咱俩跳了  - 当然
- Probably not with each other.  - Of course.
天上见了 朋友
I will see you in the skies, amigo.
观众朋友们 又到了一年之中最重要的时刻
Race fans, it's that time of year again.
欢迎来到环球之翼飞行大赛
Welcome to the Wings Around The Globe.
大家好 我是布莱恩特·穆斯塔博格
Hello, I'm Brent Mustangburger,
这是世界上最快的比赛
and this is the flagship event of the world's fastest sport
只有最强王者能够参加的旗舰赛
where only the best of the best compete.
每一个赛段都是对选手
Each leg brings a new challenge,
敏捷 导航能力和持久力的全新挑战
testing agility, navigation and endurance.
但归根结底 速度才是比赛的真正意义
But when it's all said and done, speed is the name of the game.
科林·柯林已经在肯尼迪机场
Our very own Colin Cowling
的绝佳位置给我们带来独家现场报道
is standing by live from JFK airport with the best seat in the house.
现场状况如何 大个子
How's the view, big guy?
布莱恩特 下边的状况真是让人热血沸腾
Brent, the scene below me is absolutely electric.
如你所知 我们的参赛者来自世界各地
As you know, we have racers from all over the world, here.
但其实所谓的悬念只在于
But the real story should be who's coming in second
谁会位居三届卫冕冠军里普斯林杰之后处于第二
to three-time defending champ, Ripslinger,
里普斯林杰希望成为第一位四次
who is seeking to become the first four-time winner
摘得环球之翼桂冠的选手
in the Wings Around The Globe.
选手们正在入场
The racers are making their way to the runway.
- 是达斯迪  - 喔!
- It's Dusty!  - Whoo!
好了 各位 给你们带来达斯迪周边产品
All right, everybody, get your Dusty bobbleheads.
有微波手套 帽子 车贴
Your oven mitts, hats, bumper stickers, and I also ordered
我还订了一千个纪念哨子
a thousand commemorative whistles.
你能不能帮我建个网站?
Hey, you think you can help me set up a website?
钱会烧手吗?
Does a giga bite?
好好照顾它就不会烧手
Well, not if you pet him nicely.
达斯迪
Dusty.
136个国家参与竞争
One-hundred and thirty-six nations compete.
21架飞机脱颖而出
Twenty-one planes selected.
踏入这个赛场就意味着被载入史册
Folks, a step onto this field, is a step into history.
天呐!
Holy smokes!
观众朋友们 我们的比赛中第一次出现了作物喷粉机的身影
And for the first time ever, folks, we have a crop duster in the race.
作物喷粉机?
A crop duster?
他会挂掉的
Well, he's gonna die.
里普斯林杰! 里普斯林杰!
Ripslinger! Ripslinger!
喔!
Wow!
里普斯林杰! 里普斯林杰! 里普斯林杰!
Ripslinger! Ripslinger! Ripslinger!
沉浸在欢呼声中吧!
Yeah. You're caught in the riptide!
哇 看看周围的人群
Whoa. Look at this crowd.
专注比赛 朋友 别为任何事分心
Stay focused, amigo. Don't let anything distract you.
啊!
Ay-yay!
那是谁?
Who is that vision?
瑞谢尔 加拿大拉力赛冠军
That's Rochelle, the Canadian rally champ.
她真是貌若天仙 惊为天人
She is like an angel, sent from heaven.
就像无尽黑暗中的曙光
Like a sunrise after a lifetime of darkness.
就像即将枯萎草地上的新鲜肥料
Like fresh fertilizer on a field of dying grass.
完全不是一回事 朋友
This is not your thing, my friend.
好了 选手们 启动你们的引擎吧!
All right, racers. Start your engines!
七个赛段 超过31000公里
Seven legs, over 31,000 kilometers,
世界上最高的山峰 最深的海洋
the world's highest mountains, and the deepest oceans
都在那里等待着
all stand before them
被冠军所征服
just waiting to be conquered by the right competitor.
开始了 天呐
Here we go. Oh, boy!
所有的付出与汗水
All the preparation.
都是为了这一刻
It all comes down to this moment.
场上的一架飞机最终会夺得冠军
One of these planes is about to fly off into the pages of sports history
并在体育的历史长河中被人所铭记
and become a champion.
出发!
Go!
比赛开始了!
And we are under way!
喔! 涡流!
Whoa! Swirlies!
噢!
Whoa! Whoa.
第一站的比赛就异常艰难
Our first stage is a Whopper.
第一赛段 纽约-冰岛
横跨北大西洋的死亡冲刺
A dead sprint across the North Atlantic.
没错 布莱恩特 就是如此 观众朋友们
That's right, Brent. This is how it works, folks.
这个赛段的冠军将在明天的比赛中第一个出发
The winner of the leg today is the first to take off tomorrow.
欢迎来到冰岛
看看谁是最后一名! 只会低空飞行的土鳖!
Hey, look who's finally here! It's that low-flying farmer boy!
你知道自己是在比赛吧 啊?
You do know this is a race, right?
说的好 老大
That's a good one, boss.
麻烦问一下 破冰机有多重?
Excuse me, how much does a snow plow weigh?
我不知道
Je ne sais pas. I do not know.
足够击碎冰块 我是卓帕卡布拉
Enough to break the ice. I am El Chupacabra.
- 所以你是破冰机,是吧?  - 可以这么说
- Ah. You are the snow plow, oui?  - You could say that, yes.
- 那我是冰块?  - 是的
- And I am the ice?  - Yes.
冰冷 冷漠 毫无生气?
Cold, frozen and lifeless?
不 我... 用西班牙语说会比较好
No, I... It sounds better in Spanish.
自己玩去吧 桌布破拉
Why don't you go plow yourself, El Chu-toy?
她就像天使下凡
She is like an angel.
我是普罗普沃什镇 呼叫农田守望者达斯迪
This is Propwash Junction to Dusty Crophopper.
收到 楚格
I read you, Chug.
和"大狗"一起比赛感觉如何啊?
So what's it like racing with the big dogs, Duster?
- 我的机翼冻僵了 -哇!
- Well, my wings froze solid.  - Man!
- 喷粉器上挂满了冰柱  - 不错!
- I had icicles hanging off my sprayer.  - All right!
我还差点撞在一个10层的冰山上
And I nearly smashed into a 10-story iceberg.
太棒了
Awesome!
我可不会用"太棒了"来形容
Yeah, "awesome" is not quite the word that I would use
一次可怕的鬼门关之旅
to describe a gruesome near-death experience.
撑住 哥们
You hang in there, buddy.
没什么比死在你所钟爱的事上更棒了
There's nothing better than dying while doing what you love most.
这一定让他宽慰不少
That's gonna make him feel a lot better.
达斯迪 就像乔利中队在
Dusty, just like when the Jolly Wrenches
阿留申群岛的时候一样
were up in the Aleutians
靠近海面的空气饱含水分
the air down close to the sea has more moisture,
这就是为什么你会结冰
which is why you took on ice.
- 你得试着飞得高一点  - 好吧
- You gotta try to fly higher.  - Great.
好消息是
The good news is
明天的行程是巴伐利亚障碍赛段
tomorrow's leg goes through the Bavarian obstacle course.
完全靠的是灵活性 你要抓住机会赶超对手
It's all about agility, so it's your chance to move up.
还要记住 速度不是取胜的关键 技术才是一切
And remember, it's not speed that wins races, it's skill.
第二赛段 冰岛-德国
求救! 求救! 求救! 失去飞行视野 我看不见了
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday! I'm blinded. I can't see.
我们收到最新的消息
We're receiving breaking news
在德国上空赛段 一名选手出现了事故
of an incident in the skies over Germany involving one of the racers.
切换到航拍镜头一号 进行现场直播
Let's check in with Skycam 1 for more information.
斗牛犬 英国传奇赛手
Bulldog, the legendary flyer from
正经历生死关头
the UK, is in tremendous danger.
他好像正在盲飞 失去了飞行速度和高度
It looks like he's flying blind, losing speed, losing altitude...
等等! 是7号选手 农田守望者
Wait! It's Racer Number 7, Crophopper,
- 和他一起下坠  - 他在干什么啊?
- pulling up beside him.  - What's he doing?
- 斗牛犬 上偏你的左副翼  - 明白
- Bulldog, apply your left aileron.  - Okay.
停止尾旋
Stop roll.
- 乘现在 爬升 快爬升  - 明白
- Now, quick, pull up.  - Got it.
升一点 再升一点!
Harder, harder!
微右偏 好的!
Slight roll right. Good!
哇哦! 前方大型城堡! 爬升! 右满偏!
Whoa! Big castle! Pull up! Hard roll right!
停止偏转
Stop roll.
你还在吗?
Are you still there?
我还在 我就在你旁边
I'm right here. I'll fly right alongside you.
全体注意! 收到求救信号! 清空跑道!
Achtung! We have a mayday! Clear the runway!
全体注意! 清空跑道!
Achtung! Clear the runway!
- 提升马力  - 好的
- Add power.  - Okay.
- 慢慢的  - 明白
- Easy, now.  - Yes.
好的 下降襟翼 保持住
Good. Flaps down, lock them.
小心啊
Careful.
起落架放下
Landing gear down.
明白 起落架就位
Yeah, and locked.
开始滑行减速
Begin your flare.
重心略微偏后
Power back a little.
落地! 好样的!
Touchdown! Nicely done!
谢谢你的帮助 伙计
Thanks for your help, matey.
如果不是你...
I couldn't have done it without...
你? 是你救了我?
You? You saved me?
我之前怎么跟你说的 小鬼? 大家都各自为战 懂吗?
What did I tell you, boy? Every plane for himself, right?
在我家乡 如果你看到有人坠落...
Where I come from, if you see someone falling from the sky...
没错 但这是场比赛 你现在稳稳地垫底了
Yes, but this is a competition. Now, you're dead last.
但我欠你一条命
And I owe you my life.
你是在哭吗?
Are you crying?
我没哭 我是英国人!
I don't cry, I'm British!
但还是谢谢了 伙计
Thanks, matey.
小事情 牛头犬
Sure thing, Bulldog.
牛头犬!
Bulldog!
不得不说 农用飞机 你还真是个好人
Well, I gotta say, cropduster, you are a nice guy.
嘿 谢谢 里普
Hey. Thanks, Rip.
况且我们都知道 好人没有好下场
And we all know where nice guys finish.
是啊!
Yeah!
稳稳垫底
Dead last.
不高兴 就喝酒
You sad, you drink.
多谢了 好建议啊
Thanks. Great advice.
至少你没有情场失意啊
At least you are not last in the race for love.
瑞谢尔?
Rochelle?
这让人心碎 她的热情与我无关
Her passion is, sadly, not for me.
她很难追吧 卓帕
Tough break, El Chu.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我叫弗兰茨 我是你的粉丝
My name is Franz, and I am a huge fan.
- 我还有粉丝?  - 哦 就我一个人
- I have fans?  - Oh, no, no, no. Just me.
我代表所有小型飞机 想向你说声感谢
And I would like to say danke for representing all us little planes.
啊... 可你是辆车
Uh... You're a car.
没错 没错 但请称我飞行汽车弗兰茨
Yeah, yeah, yeah. But I am what you call a Flugzeugauto,
迄今六辆飞行汽车中的一辆!
one of only six flying cars ever built!
- 哇哦!  - 你好啊 达斯迪先生
- Whoa!  - Guten Tag, Herr Dusty.
我是冯·弗里根豪森
I am Von Fliegenhozen.
你刚刚不是说 你叫弗兰茨吗?
Didn't you just say your name was Franz?
不是 不是
Nein, nein, nein.
弗兰茨是那个没骨气的家伙
Franz is a guy with no spine
在地上运石头的时候他管事儿
who is in charge when we putter about the cobblestones.
在空中 我说了算
In the air, I am in charge.
这家伙急需检查一下脑子啊
This guy needs to get his head gasket checked.
严重的人格分裂啊
Serious identity issues.
戴面具还敢说这种话?
This from the one wearing a mask?
说得好
Touché.
我们都为你加油 达斯迪先生
We are both pulling for you, Herr Dusty.
谢谢你的支持 我现在缺少的就是支持
Thanks for the support. I need all the help I can get.
我还有业余的建议
I have a humble suggestion.
如果没有了那些罐子管子
Would you not be much faster
你不是可以轻装飞行 飞得更快吗?
without the pipes and tank and whatnot weighing you down?
我的喷粉器 又来?
My Sprayer. Again?
是啊 为什么坚持这多余的重量呢?
Yeah. Why carry around the extra weight?
这疯子小车还是有点道理的
The little crazy car is right.
也许你应该像个赛手一样思考问题了
Perhaps you need to start thinking like a racer.
这拆了还是可以装回去的 是吧?
This is reversible, right?
哦! 哦 嘿 你下手轻点啊 好吗?
Oh! Oh. Hey, you're being careful down there, right?
哇哦 哦! 好了 凉飕飕的
Whoa. Ooh! Yep, that's cold.
那?
So?
你们觉得呢?
So, what do you think?
好极了 达斯迪
Wunderbar, Dusty.
完美了
Fantastico.
一身轻松啊 不是吗?
It is freeing, yes?
没错 我要说的就是这点
Yeah, you took the words right out of my mouth.
再见了 喷粉器!
Bye-bye, sprayer!
谢谢你 弗兰茨... 哦 冯·弗里根豪森
Thanks for everything, Franz... Er, Von Fliegenhozen.
祝你好运 达斯迪先生
Guten luck, Herr Dusty.
现在到了第三个赛段
It's our third leg
德国-印度
一些选手也因为机械故障而不得不退出比赛
and we've already lost several competitors to equipment failure.
但比赛的看点 布莱恩特 是农田守望者达斯迪
But the real story here, Brent, is Dusty Crophopper.
没错
Absolutely.
他正在一步步地赶超上来
He's passing one flier after another.
没错 这家伙本来是用来给庄稼撒药的
That's right. This guy was built to dust crops,
但他在比赛中 可谓绝尘而去啊
but he's dusting the competition.
之后的赛段呢 科林?
What's next, Colin?
布莱恩特 接下去 可是达斯迪的拿手赛段了
Brent, this could be Crophopper's leg, all the way.
选手们必须在1000英尺下方飞行
The racers will have to fly under a hard ceiling of 1,000 feet.
直面乌云和山峰
Stay under the clouds and in the hills.
20号选手被取消资格
Number 20 is disqualified.
- 动作真棒  - 难以置信
- What a move.  - Incredible.
- 看这个径向过载弯  - 哦嘢!
- Look at that radial-G pass.  - Oh, yeah!
从最后一名 一直追赶到第八名
From last place, all the way up to eighth.
里普斯林杰先生 比赛就是你的人生
Mr. Ripslinger, you were built for racing.
印度 阿格拉空军基地
没错! 你懂的
Yeah! You know it.
农用飞机怎么可能超过你呢?
So how can a crop duster out-fly you?
- 等下 你说什么?  - 他在那里!
- Wait, what?  - There he is!
达斯迪!
Dusty!
- 哇哦!  - 你是怎么跟上专业选手的脚步的?
- Wow!  - How do you keep up with the pros?
是干农活 让你变的更强壮的吗?
Did working on the farm make you stronger?
达斯迪! 为什么你选择低飞?
Dusty! Why do you fly so low?
他们为什么要花时间报道他呢?
Why are they wasting their time with him?
他就是个带翅膀的拖拉机
He's a tractor with wings.
这完全就是草根搏上位的传统故事
Actually, it's a really compelling underdog story.
就好比"洛基"
It's like Rocky.
还有"戴维和歌利亚"
It's more like David and Goliath.
- 还有老黄狗  - 那不是讲草根族的电影
- Or Old Yeller.  - That's not an underdog story.
- 里面明明有草  - 够了!
- Well, there's a dog in it.  - Enough!
是啊 够了!
Yeah, enough!
结局老黄狗被杀了 你两个笨蛋
You know, they shot Old Yeller at the end, you twits.
哦! 被剧透了!
Oh! Spoiler alert!
这样下去 我们就跟那种条幅机 拉烟机和货机混为一谈了
Soon, we'll be overrun by every banner tower, skywriter and air freighter
那群自不量力的家伙
who thinks they can be one of us.
那乡巴佬已经得意忘形 都忘了自己从哪来的了
That farm boy forgot who he is and where he came from.
他别想阻止我创造历史
He's not about to stop me from making history.
达斯迪 达斯迪 你比赛的技巧是从哪里学来的啊?
Dusty, Dusty, where did you learn to race?
从我的教练 斯基珀
From my coach, Skipper.
他也是我参赛的原因 他是个极其出色的教练
He's the reason I'm even here. He's an amazing instructor.
也是一位人生的挚友
And a great friend.
他在全球执行过无数次任务
He flew dozens of missions all around the world.
我保证 如果他能的话 他肯定会一路陪着我的
And I'm sure, if he could, he'd be with us right now.
哇哦 你的引擎听上去有点锈了
Whoa, your engine sounds kind of rough.
肯定是内燃机错火了
Must be a mag misfire.
况且今晚天气也不适合飞行
It's probably not a good night for flying anyway.
- 好的 下次见啦  - 嘿 你有新玩意了吗?
- Okay. Come back soon.  - Hey, you got anything new?
那你就问对人了
I'm glad you asked.
现在正是推出限量款的达斯迪纪念杯
I'm now selling these one-of-a-kind Dusty commemorative mugs.
怎么样?
Huh?
哇哦!
Whoa!
达斯迪呼叫...
This is Dusty Crophopper calling...
- 我过10分钟就回来  - 达斯迪 第八名了啊!
- I'll be back in 10.  - Dusty, eighth place!
干得好啊 达斯超人!
Way to go, Dustmeister!
- 嘿! 你终于把M5000去掉啦  - 他的什么?
- Hey! You finally removed your M5000.  - His what?
他的5000型空用微型涂敷器
His Micro-Air-5000-D-L Aerial Applicator.
说车话
Use your words.
他的喷粉器
His sprayer.
没错! 喷粉器
Right! Sprayer.
达斯迪 明天可是个长赛段啊
Dusty, you got a big leg tomorrow.
- 是啊  - 你觉得怎么样?
- Yeah.  - How you feeling?
难以置信啊 伟大的喜马拉雅山脉
I can't believe it. The mighty Himalayas.
达斯迪 那里的山脉
Dusty, that vertical wind shear
四处都是致命的垂直涡流
is going to be wicked over those mountains.
其实 身处那种海拔的好处是
Well, the good thing about being that high up,
那边氧气不充足
you see, there's not a lot of oxygen.
所以如果你坠机的话 也不会爆炸什么的
So, if you crash, no explosion.
好极了 楚格
Great, Chug.
当然啦 你可也能死于低温症
Of course, you could die of hypothermia
雪崩也可能让你丧命的
or an avalanche could get you.
当然啦 还有肺炎甚至冻伤
Then, of course, there's pneumonia, or even frostbite.
楚格 楚格 我知道了
Chug, Chug, I got it.
斯基普 如果我想穿过山脉
Skip, what if a guy wanted to fly
而不是飞跃山脉呢?
through the mountains instead of over them?
坏点子 我们中队在支援昆明战役中
Bad idea. The Wrenches flew through terrain like that
曾经走过那条路 多蒂没说错
in the Assault of Kunming. And Dottie is right.
气流爬升过山顶之后 会产生涡流扰动
Wind coming over the peaks can stir up rotors
扰动会让你一落千丈的
that'll drag you right down.
如果问我的话 那就蒙着脑子往上飞
If you ask me, it's time to lug-nut up.
其实你比你想象的要飞得高
You can fly a whole lot higher than you think.
- 明白了  - 你好 心上人
- Roger that.  - Hola, corazón.
- 你累了吗?  - 什么?
- Are you tired?  - What?
因为你在我脑子里 已经飞了一整天了 从未停过
Because you have been flying through my mind, nonstop.
嘛 就这么小的地方 我怎么会累呢?
Hmm. And why would I be tired flying through such a teeny, tiny space, huh?
你别装啦 其实你喜欢我
You can only pretend for so long.
嘿 卓帕 到底怎么了?
Hey, El Chu, what's the problem?
她就像灯火 而就是扑火的飞蛾
I am Icarus and she is the sun.
我飞向她的怀抱 却燃烧了我自己
I fly too close and I melt.
也许是因为你做的太过了
Maybe you're trying too hard.
也许 你要做的就是 走过去 说声...
Look, all you got to do is go over, open your mouth and say...
你好
Hello.
哇... 啊...
Wha... Uh...
哇哦
Whoa.
卓帕卡布拉!
El Chupacabra!
好像有人叫我 我先走一步了
I think someone is calling me. I have to go.
我恭喜你所获得的成就 达斯迪
I wanted to compliment you on your success, Dusty.
你第一次比赛做的很好
You're doing very well for your first race.
啊 从你嘴里说出来 的确意义重大
Aw, that means a lot, coming from you.
而且 毕竟
I mean, come on,
空体画报称你为世上最符合空气动力学的飞机啊
you were named most aerodynamic racer by Air Sports Illustrated.
要我说的话 你真是太随风舞动了
And let me just say, you are so aerodynamic.
达斯迪
Dusty.
为什么这里这么多拖拉机啊?
What's with all the tractors around here?
他们是神圣的动物(印度侍牛为神物)
They're sacred.
很多人相信 我们来生会成为拖拉机
Many believe that we will be recycled as tractors.
哦 我很相信来生的
Oh. Well, I believe in recycling.
你有看过泰姬玛哈陵吗?
Have you ever been to the Taj Mahal?
没有 我还没去过
No. No, I haven't.
快点 我们一起去吧
Come on. Let's go.
在家的感觉肯定很好
It must be nice to be back home.
其实 心里还蛮复杂的 我有上百万的粉丝
Well, it's complicated. I have a billion fans.
而且他们都希望我能赢
And they're all expecting me to win.
也许这次冠军就是你啊
Maybe this time, you will.
哇哦
Wow.
这地方太漂亮了
This place is amazing.
的确啊
It really is.
等明天 你就会飞跃那宏伟的喜马拉雅山脉了
And tomorrow, you'll fly over the magnificent Himalayas.
那些小山? 是啊... 小事一件啦
Those little hills? Yeah, well... No big deal.
你喜欢低飞 不是吗?
You like to fly low, don't you?
哦 哦? 那是 啊 那是我的策略
Oh. Oh, that? Uh, that's strategic.
空气密度啊 引擎燃烧率啊...
Air density and, uh, combustion...
你知道吗 你可以贴着铁指针飞的
You know, you could follow the Iron Compass, instead.
- 铁指针?  - 是啊 那是火车轨道
- Iron Compass?  - Yeah, rail road tracks.
穿越山脉和峡谷 你可以一直低飞前行
Through a valley in the mountains, so you can still fly low.
真的?
Really?
谢谢了 伊莎妮
Thanks, Ishani.
不用谢
Anytime.
第4赛段 印度-尼泊尔
所有选手的噩梦就是飞跃喜马拉雅山脉
Every racer's nightmare is scaling the Himalayas.
前方虽然是短途赛段 但是极度的危险
It's a short leg ahead, but extremely treacherous.
不
No.
哦! 啊!
OW! Ah!
哇哦!
Whoa!
哦...
Uh...
有人吗?
Hello?
这是我该来的地方吗?
Is this where I'm supposed to be?
这也是生命的重要命题之一啊
That is one of life's great questions.
我死了!
I'm dead!
农田守望者先生
Mr. Crophopper.
欢迎来尼泊尔
Welcome to Nepal.
我不明白 其他人都走了吗?
I don't understand. Have the others left already?
实际上 还没有人抵达呢
Actually, no one else is here yet.
你是第一个到达的
You're in first place.
真的?
Really?
他穿过了一个什么?!
He flew through a what?!
- 隧道?  - 太疯狂了!
- A tunnel?  - That is crazy!
是啊 比火狐还疯狂
Si, crazy like a Firefox.
达斯迪 获得第一有什么感想吗?
Dusty, how does it feel to be in First place?
感觉不错
It feels great.
但最重要的是 我真高兴我低空穿越了隧道
But more than anything, I'm just happy I fit through that tunnel.
朋友们 我想说 如果你陷入困境了就...
Guys, I gotta tell you, if you're ever in a tight squeeze just...
朋友们 借过下
Excuse me, guys.
疯狂的一天 对吧
Crazy day today, huh?
哦 是 今天你赢得漂亮
Oh. Yeah, a very exciting win for you today.
你真是冒了一个挺大的险
Quite a risk you took.
确实 确实 对了 你的螺旋桨 是新的么
Yeah, yeah. Hey, your propeller, is it new?
哦 是啊
Oh. I suppose it is.
裂天者5号 对吧?
Sky Slycer Mark Five, right?
里普斯林杰竞技队的专用螺旋桨是不?
Aren't those made exclusively for Ripslinger's race team?
- 是么?  - 是 是 确实是
- Are they?  - Yeah. Yeah, they are.
达斯迪...
Dusty...
- 你陷害我  - 真的 我真心不想伤害你的
- You set me up.  - Look, I didn't ever want to hurt you.
- 为什么这样?  - 情况很复杂 真的?
- Why?  - it's complicated, okay?
你今天差点害我死翘了
You could have gotten me killed out there today.
我但是真以为你会掉头
I really thought that you'd just turn around.
哼 你以为错了
Well, you were wrong.
我看错你了
And I was wrong about you.
哎 里普 谢你让我赢了
Hey, Rip. Thanks for first place.
凭着低空快飞的
Flying low and quick,
农田守望者达斯迪始终位居榜首
Dusty Crophopper is managing to hold on to the top spot.
卫冕冠军里普斯林杰紧随其后
But current reigning champ, Ripslinger, is just seconds behind him.
这场精彩的冠军比赛
This surprise battle for first place
第五赛段 尼泊尔-中国
让农田守望者达斯迪成为聚焦点
has made Dusty Crophopper the one to watch.
他成为了全世界的平民英雄
He's become a working-class hero around the globe.
哇
Whoa!
我说过他做得到
I told you he could do it.
- 够了  - 啊 别!
- That's it.  - Wha. .. Aw!
我的skypad 老兄
That was my skyPad, man.
再过两周就出新款了
A new one's coming out in two weeks.
中国 上海
你让他们见识了一流赛手的手段啊?
You're really showing them big-time racers a thing or two, huh?
是啊 斯基普 明天我们要飞太平洋了
Yeah. We head out across the Pacific tomorrow, Skip.
你在那待过一段时间 对吧
You were stationed there for a while, right?
- 对  - 给点什么建议?
- Yeah.  - Got any advice?
回想41年的威克岛之战
Back in '41, during the Battle over Wake Island
我们当时遭遇了强烈的季风
the Wrenches ran into serious monsoons
其强度直接可以瞬间折断你的机翼
with embedded CBs that could tear your wings right off.
小心的 还有一件事...
Be careful. And one more thing...
我为你感到骄傲 达斯迪
I'm proud of you, Dusty.
谢谢 僚机
Thanks, Wingman.
嗨 达斯迪 给你个惊喜
Hey, Dusty, we have a surprise for you.
哦 哦 哦! 让我告诉他
Oh, oh, oh! You have to let me tell him.
你说 楚格
Go ahead, Chug.
额... 哦 我知道了 就是... 就要说出口了
Uh... Oh, I know it. It's... It's on the tip of my tongue.
我想想
I'll remember.
我们打算...
We're going...
打算...
- 去...  - 去...
- to...  - to...
- 嗯...  - 马来...
- Mmm...  - Malays...
- 墨西哥  - 墨西哥! 就这个!
- Mexico.  - Mexico! That's it!
- 我们在墨西哥相见  - 真的?
- We're going to meet you in Mexico.  - Really?
对 斯帕奇和我花钱买了票
Yep. Tickets are on Sparky and me.
我们卖了326个你的小公仔 142个天线球
We sold 326 Dusty bobbleheads, 143 antenna balls,
203个旋杯...
203 spinner mugs...
还有1000个口哨 加油 达斯迪汉子队! 冠军! 耶!
And 1,000 whistles. Go, Team Dusterino! The winner! Yeah!
你确定你也要来吗 斯基珀?
You sure you're up for it, Skipper?
当然啦 反正不是我自己飞
You bet. Somebody else is doing the flying.
兄弟们 真是个好消息 墨西哥不见不散
That's great news, guys. I'll see you in Mexico.
晚安!
Buenas noches!
我要买辣茄酱! 喔喔!
I'll bring the Salsa! Whoo-hoo!
嗨 卓帕 哪起火了?
Hey, El Chu, where's the fire?
在我的灵魂里
It is in my soul.
今晚 我要赢得
Tonight, I shall win the heart
瑞谢尔小姐的欢心
of Miss Rochelle.
啊!
Ugh!
悲剧 悲剧 悲剧 千年悲剧
No, no, no. A thousand no's.
达斯迪 你在干嘛?
Dusty, what are you doing?
要循序渐进
Low and slow.
怎么循序渐进
要温文尔雅
哦...
Oh...
啥意思?
What does that mean?
没听懂 但是加拿大法语在魁北克是爱的语言
No idea, but French-Canadian is the language of love in Quebec.
所以 还不错的节奏
So, it's got to be good.
哥们 我欠你一人情
I'm in your debt, compadre.
如果需要我 随传随到
If ever you need me, I shall be there.
哥们 这个我喜欢
Compadre. I like that.
欢迎收看
You are looking live
上海浦东国际机场现场直播
at Pudong Shanghai International Airport...
看吧 榜首对一个乡巴佬来说感觉不错
Yep. first place. Not too bad for a farm boy.
哦 是么?
Oh. yeah?
榜首是失败者之地
Well, First place is for losers.
说不够了 笨蛋!
Can it, moron!
嗷!
Ow!
现在 听着 现在该你们有用武之地的时候了
Now, listen up. It's time to make yourselves useful.
你怎么了?
What happened to you?
就那首歌 威力太猛了
That song. It flipped a switch.
哦 小坏蛋 过来嘛
Oh, my little monster. Come here.
慢点! 不!
Please! No!
她现在就跟母豹一样
She is like a jaguar now.
哦 小甜心
Oh, my little burrito.
温柔点!
Be gentle with me!
启动引擎
Start your engines.
这是我们第六场也是赛程最长的一场比赛
This is our sixth and longest leg.
因为这里与墨西哥横跨一个大洋
These racers will need to follow their GPS antennas
第六赛段 中国-墨西哥
主要考验赛手们的导航能力
because there's a big ocean between here and Mexico.
啊!
Ah!
我的天线!
My antenna!
哦 不! 不! 不!
Oh, no! No! No!
我该怎么办?
What am I going to do?
最后的已知坐标
Last known coordinates,
26度 31分
26 degrees, 31 minutes.
呼叫夏威夷?
Hawaii, are you there?
收到没? 我燃料不足
Do you read? I am low on fuel.
哦 不!
Oh, no!
哦 天啊
Oh, boy.
喔 喔 喔 喔 喔
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
未知飞机 未知飞机 你进入受限领空
Unknown rider, unknown rider. You have entered restricted airspace.
为什么不回应无线电呼叫?
Why haven't you responded to radio contact?
有人撞断了我的天线
Somebody cut off my antenna.
- 请表明身份  - 我是农田守望者达斯迪
- Identify yourself.  - I'm Dusty Crophopper.
收到
Roger that.
闯入者名为农田守望者7号
Bogey has been identified as Crophopper Seven.
我已经在烧油气了 我需要降落
I'm running on vapors. I need to land.
你空油飞行做什么?
What are you doing out here with an empty tank?
我本打算去夏威夷加油 但是...
I thought I'd refuel in Hawaii, but...
夏威夷在离这里375英里的西南方
Hawaii is 375 miles southwest of here.
- 什么?  - 听着 农田守望者
- What?  - Listen, Crophopper.
你最好跟我们到船上去
You better follow us to the boat.
附近可没酒吧
No Bingo fields around here.
- "酒吧"?  - 降落的地方
- "Bingo fields"?  - Places to land.
- 船?  - 美国海军飞森豪威尔号航空母舰
- The boat?  - The USS Dwight D. Flysenhower.
B组 返回成员增加一位 确认
Bravo, checking in as frag plus one. Check.
- 二  - 允许着陆 B组
- Two.  - Go ahead, Bravo.
闯入者是平民 需要紧急燃料
Bogey is civilian. Needs emergency fuel.
- 收到  - 大点声!
- Copy that.  - For flying out loud!
真糟糕 一个平民就要在我的甲板上爆炸了
That's all I need, a civilian exploding on my deck.
长官 我们可以设路障
We could rig the barricade, sir.
所有引擎 全速向前
All engines, ahead flank.
Aye, Captain. All engines ahead flank.
- 设路障  - 收到
- Rig the barricade.  - Copy that.
设路障! 快点 快点
Rig the barricade! Chop-chop. Hubba-hubba.
我们带你飞向路障
Let's line you up for the barricade.
你要做的就是收油 降落
All you have to do is throttle on back and call the ball
然后祈祷那些面条能拉得住你
and hopefully end up in the Spaghetti.
什么? 等一下 不 等一下! 等一下!
What? Wait, no, wait! Wait a second!
大哥 我不一定做得到啊
Guys, I'm not sure I can do this.
我看你别无选择
I don't see how you have a choice.
好吧 但是跑道还在移动
Okay. But that runway is moving.
我们会带你飞上滑行道的
We'll set you up on the glide path.
跑道怎么能动呢
Runways are not supposed to move.
行 我还行 我会没事的
Okay. I'm okay. I'm going to be fine.
- 放轻松  - 移动跑道 移动跑道
- Take it easy.  - Moving runway, moving runway.
- 就这样 来吧  - 收油门
- There it is. Here we go.  - Throttle on back.
或许我要重新来一次
Maybe if I just came around again.
- 平衡你的机翼  - 放轻松
- Level your wings.  - Easy with it.
停 停 停!
Cut, cut, cut!
停!
Stop!
没事了 农田守望者
We've got you, Crophopper.
来吧 来修理一下 加个油 再重回赛场
Come on, let's get you fixed up, refueled and back in the race.
你现在落后了
You are way behind.
谢了 哥们 你救了我
Thanks, guys. You saved my tail out there.
- 胜利  - 胜利
- Victory.  - Victory.
嗨 那是什么?
Hey, what is that?
那是乔利扳手中队名人墙
That's the Jolly Wrenches Wall of Fame.
每一位飞行者 每一个使命
Every flyer, every mission.
嗯... 斯基珀... 斯基珀...
Mmm... Skipper... Skipper...
哦 哈哈! 在这
Oh. Ha-ha! There he is.
等一下 我不明白了 为什么只有一个任务?
Wait. I don't understand. Why is there only one mission?
楚格 那都是些什么啊?
Chug, what's all that?
我从来没出过国 你知道 我还带着腹泻药
Well, I've never been out of the country. You know, I brought the Commodium.
不管你做什么 别乱喝汽油
Whatever you do, don't drink the petrol.
我们就去两天
We're only going for two days.
好好准备 对吧
Got to be prepared, right?
还有海滩装 晚礼服 内衣
Got beachwear, dinner wear, underwear...
达斯迪呼叫斯基珀? 请回话 斯基珀
Dusty Skipper? Come in, Skipper.
达斯迪 我们现在去墨西哥
Dusty! We're heading off to Mexico right now.
幸好你没事
Glad you got there safe.
天气预报说那边有一场大暴雨
Weather report says a major storm is brewing out there.
我不在墨西哥 我和乔利中队在一起
I'm not in Mexico. I'm with the Jolly Wrenches.
你在飞森豪威尔号上?
You're on the Flysenhower?
哎 我看到那个名人墙了 那个榜单上你就有一个任务
Hey, I saw the Wall of Fame. They only list one mission for you.
达斯迪 如果你没有躲过风暴 你就要...
Dusty, if you're not past that storm yet, you need...
不对 那个肯定错了
That can't be right. it must be a mistake.
听着 你一定要逃出来
Look, you have to get out of there.
你一定要飞高点
You're going to have to fly high.
是真的么?
Is it true?
听我说 要在风暴上空飞!
Listen to me, get above the storm!
- 斯基珀 是真的么?  - 是真的!
- Skipper, is it true?  - It's true!
是真的
It's true.
我只飞了一个任务
I only flew one mission.
但之前那些故事呢?
But all those stories?
农田守望者 天气系统运行很快
Crophopper, we got weather moving in fast.
尽快起飞 否则来不及了
You've got to take off before it's too late.
给我点时间
I just need a second here.
这样不好 孩子
That's a negative, son.
现在不走 就再也走不了了
You don't go now, you don't go at all.
警报 天气中心发出警告
Be advised, the JTWC has issued a tropical cyclone formation alert
东北太平洋形成热带气旋
for the northeast Pacific ocean.
主要影响区域为
Area of convection is located 500 nautical miles
夏威夷东北方五百英里
east-northeast of Hawaii.
最高持续风速 目前估计...
Maximum sustained surface winds are currently estimated at...
到2号发射台报到
Report to catapult two.
"小猫"可以让你在2秒内速度由零提高到160节
The CAT will take you from zero to 160 knots in two seconds.
小猫(CAT 蒸汽弹射系统)
两秒?
Two seconds?
我们要给你称重再设置一下蒸汽压力
We're going to check your weight and set the steam pressure.
记住 一旦起飞就直线上升
Remember, climb straight ahead once you get airborne.
- 直线上升  - 飞行至风暴之上
- Climb straight ahead.  - Get above the storm.
好 马力全开 准备就绪就点头示意发射员
Okay, engine full throttle. Nod to the shooter when you're set.
达斯迪 为扳手中队而战
Go win it for the Wrenches, Dusty.
为真理而飞行!
Volo Pro Veritas!
顶风正常 压力正常
Head Wind's good. Pressure's good.
二号发射台 走你
Go on CAT two.
里普斯林杰先生 关于农田守望者达斯迪失踪一事
Se?or Ripslinger, any comment
墨西哥 墨西哥城
请谈几句吧?
on the disappearance of Dusty Crophopper?
达斯迪是个好人 他毫不畏惧
Dusty was a nice guy who flew the challenge
挑战自我 直击长空
and pierced the clouds of mediocrity.
我们都会想他的 让一下
We're all going to miss him. Excuse me.
希望他下辈子投胎做船而不是飞机
Let's just hope he makes a better boat than a plane.
说得好 老板
That's a good one, boss.
哦 是 挺好的
Oh, yeah, that was pretty good.
达斯迪比你快10倍
Se?or Dusty has 10 times the engine you do.
比你正直10倍
And 10 times the integrity.
你装着我们崭新的螺旋桨对我说这些
Said the plane with the shiny new propeller.
为那玩意你付出了多少正直啊 亲爱的?
How much integrity did that one cost you, sweetheart?
付出的太多了
Too much.
你过去是个多棒的冠军
You used to be a great champion.
如今你都堕落成这般
How the mighty have fallen.
你被扇披风都不够资格
You are not even worthy of a cape swish.
是吗?
Really?
怎么可能就只完成了一件任务?
How can it be only one mission?
航空线之争
The Battle of Airway.
图洪加港突袭 阿留申群岛
The raid in Tujunga Harbor. The Aleutians.
威克岛战役 支援昆明
The Battle of Wake Island. The Assault on Kunming.
我得飞到风暴上面去!
I gotta get above the storm!
哇!
Whoa!
求救! 求救! 我要坠落了!
Mayday! Mayday! I'm going down!
北纬18度6分 119...
18 degrees north, six minutes, 119...
救命!
Help!
- 达斯迪!  - 我的朋友!
- Dusty!  - Mi amigo!
快 到机库去
Quick, to the hangar.
翼肋折断 齿轮扭曲 支柱弯曲
Broken wing ribs, twisted gear, bent prop,
主翼梁严重损坏
and your main spar is cracked bad.
结束了
It's over.
就一个?
One mission?
还说什么为真理而飞行
So much for Volo Pro Veritas.
我们能单独待一会么?
Can we get a minute alone, please?
你也去吧 斯帕奇
You, too, Sparky.
我在乔利扳手中队第一次巡航任务是在格兰戴尔运河
My first patrol as a Jolly Wrench was at Glendal Canal.
我的小队里全是新兵 都是崭新的
My squadron was all rookies. All razor sharp.
我本该小心的
I should know.
他们每一个都是由我训练出来的
I trained every single one of them.
本来是一次例行巡航 非常简单
It was supposed to be a routine patrol. A milk run.
看 斯基珀 两点钟方向 两英里处有敌舰
Look, Skipper, enemy ship two o'clock low, two miles.
- 轻松干一票 你说呢?  - 不行 线锯二号
- Easy pickings. What do you say?  - Negative, Jigsaw Two.
我们的命令是侦查和回报
Our orders are to recon and report back.
行了 斯基珀 速战速决
Come on, Skip, it will be a turkey shoot.
- 干吧 斯基珀  - 是啊 干吧!
- Let's do it, Skipper.  - Yeah, come on!
好吧 我们离近点看看
All right. Let's go in for a closer look.
不过要保持距离
But keep your distance.
天呐! 这是整支舰队!
Holy Cow! It's the whole enemy fleet!
再想爬升已经来不及了
It was too late to pull up.
躲开 卢卡斯!
Get out of there, Lucas!
我的整个小队
My whole squadron.
在我的指挥下
Under my command.
从那之后 我就再也不能飞了
After that, I just couldn't bring myself to fly again.
我问你个问题吧 达斯迪
Let me ask you something, Dusty.
如果你知道我过去的真相
If you knew the truth about my past,
你还会找我来训练你吗?
would you have asked me to train you?
不会
No.
抱歉 达斯迪
I'm sorry, Dusty.
医疗救护站
达斯迪?
Dusty?
你相信吗?
Can you believe it?
他一直把我蒙在鼓里
He hasn't been straight with me this whole time.
至少你还是诚实的
At least you were honest.
你说我不是这块料
You said I wasn't built for this.
我真该听你的
I guess I should have listened to you.
达斯迪 你要是听了我的我肯定不会原谅自己
Dusty, if you had listened to me I would never ever forgive myself.
是这样 斯基珀的做法可能是有点问题
Look, the Skipper may have been wrong for what he did,
不过他看你看的很准
but he was right about you.
你不是架农用飞机 你是个赛手
You're not a crop duster. You're a racer.
而现在
And now,
全世界都知道了
the whole world knows it.
谢谢 多蒂
Thanks, Dottie.
这对我很重要
That means a lot.
我已经飞了很远了 我完蛋了 看看我
I've gone as far as I can go. I'm busted up, look at me.
是啊 看看你
Yes, look at you.
达斯迪 我无法忍受比赛里没有你
Dusty, I cannot bear the thought of competing without you.
嘿 这可是T-33 天狐的机翼
Hey, that's the wing of a T-33 Shooting Star.
当伟大的墨西哥空军需要援助的时候
When the great Mexican Air Force needed help,
美国的天狐来了 他们没有提条件
American T-33s came. They did not ask questions.
也丝毫没有犹豫 他们就来了
They did not hesitate. They were there.
因为朋友就是干这个的
Because that is what compadres do.
那个呢?
And what's that?
那个是我的午餐 别动呦
That is my lunch. Don't touch.
不过机翼是给你的
But the wings are yours.
卓帕 我很感激...
El Chu, I really appreciate...
不用说了
Silencio.
毕竟 你帮我赢得了芳心
After all, you helped me with my pursuits of the heart.
现在我们来帮你了
Now we are here to help you.
- 我们?  - 是啊
- We?  - Oui.
祝你明天好运 达斯迪 我为跟你同场竞技而自豪
Good luck tomorrow, Dusty. I am so proud to compete with you.
你很不错 达斯迪 看 这是个卫星导航器
You're a good egg, Dusty. Look, here's a sat-nav device.
防止...
Just in case...
防止你迷失了航向 其实 没有...
In case you ever find yourself lost, you know, without a...
没有朋友帮你的话
Without a friend to help you through it.
谢谢 牛头犬
Thank you, Bulldog.
送你个流量控制阀门
Here's a flow control valve for you.
来个发动机吧?
How about a starter generator?
很荣幸与你同飞
It is honor to fly beside you.
谢谢 大家 真的很感谢
Thanks, everyone. Really.
太棒了
This is fantastic.
看起来你现在需要的就是个...
Looks like all you need now is a...
新的螺旋桨了吧?
A new propeller?
来个裂天者五型的怎么样?
How about a Sky Slycer Mark Five?
等等 那是你的螺旋桨 你还是可以赢得比赛的
Wait, that's your propeller. You could still win the race.
哦 我是想赢 不过要用我自己的老螺旋桨来赢
Oh, I intend to, but with my old propeller.
这个真的不适合我
This one didn't really suit me.
不过我估计你用上会很不错的
But I think you will have a lot better luck with it.
谢谢 伊莎妮
Thanks, lshani.
多蒂 你能修好我吗?
Dottie, can you fix me?
PT6涡桨发动机带多级压缩机吗?
Does a PT6A have a multi-stage compressor?
呃...
Uh...
能! 当然能
Yes! Yes it does.
好了 伙计们 我们给他准备比赛吧
All right, you guys, let's get him ready to race.
这个是...
This one's...
什么?
What?
嗯
Hmm.
我们在墨西哥为您现场直播 他们来了
We are live from Mexico. And here they come.
好了 观众朋友们 最后一段飞回纽约的比赛
This is it, race fans. The final leg back to New York.
喔 伙计!
VVhoa, dude!
- 我们纽约再见  - 谢谢 伙计们
- We'll see you in New York.  - Thanks, guys.
达斯迪大展身手!
It's dustin' time!
达斯迪 宝贝!
Dusty Ia vista, baby!
你该给他的 他没有放弃
You gotta hand it to him. He never gives up.
行了 楚格 我们还要赶飞机
Come on, Chug, we have a jet to catch.
纽约 终点线 我们来了!
New York City. Finish line, here we come!
嘿 那么你准备好了吗 斯基珀?
Hey. So are you ready to go, Skip?
也许没准备好更好一些
Probably best if I don't.
什么...
What...
哦 好吧
Oh. Okay.
你确定?
Are you sure?
是的
Yeah.
- 达斯迪!  - 他回来了
- Dusty!  - He's back.
你逗我的吧
You got to be kidding me.
- 那个是谁?  - 是那架农用飞机
- Who's that guy?  - It's the crop duster.
- 又来一架?  - 还是那架 憨货
- Another one?  - It's the same one, Knucklehead.
躲开 白痴们
Move aside, idiots.
装几个新零件改变不了你本身
Bolting on a few new parts doesn't change who you are.
我仍然能闻到你身上的农场味道
I can still smell the farm on you.
其实呢 我终于明白了
You know what? I finally get it.
你是害怕被一架农用飞机打败
You're afraid of getting beat by a crop duster.
哦 注意身后 我会赶上来的
Well, check six, because I'm coming.
你们这些小鬼看什么呢?
And what are you punks looking at?
- 没什么 没什么  - 抱歉
- Nothing. Nothing.  - Sorry.
我们要了结这一切 彻底了结
We are going to end this, once and for all.
- 是的 老大  - 会很有意思的
- Yeah, man.  - This is going to be fun.
这一赛段全部重点就在于速度和拼尽全力的决心
This one's all about speed and the willingness to give it all.
第七赛段 墨西哥-纽约
第一个冲破纽约终点线将获得桂冠和荣誉
First to cut the ribbon in New York takes home the trophy and the glory.
耶!
Ya!
我们等第一批起飞后出发
And we're off as the first flyers take to the air.
我会在终点线等你的 美人
I will wait for you at the finish line, hermosa.
不 不 不 是我等你
No, no, no. I will be waiting for you.
耶!
Ya!
其余选手陆续起飞
The rest of the field is now off and running.
虽然农田守望者没有完成上一赛段的比赛
And though Crophopper did not complete the previous leg,
比赛官方判定是因为他的无线电受损
race officials ruled his radio had been tampered with.
所以允许他继续参赛
So he'll be allowed to compete.
不过要被罚扣时间
But with a severe time penalty.
我从来没有见过有人从如此落后的位置追上来过
I've never seen someone come back from this far behind.
为了获得机会即需要马力
It's going to take both horsepower and willpower,
又需要动力
to even have a chance.
干得漂亮 达斯迪
Good show, Dusty.
- 呃 老大?  - 怎么了?
- Um, boss?  - What?
他来了
He's here.
好的 我们已经脱离监控范围了
Okay, we're out of camera range.
你们知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
- 嘿 乡巴佬  - 你该下去耕地了
- Hey, farmer.  - Time to plow the fields.
看来你没有高度了 农田守望者
Looks like you've run out of airspace, Crophopper.
嘿!
Hey!
- 斯基珀? 喔!  - 达斯迪 爬升!
- Skipper? Whoa!  - Dusty, pull up!
斯基珀? 你飞起来了!
Skipper? You're flying!
哦 被你发现了
Oh, you noticed.
听着 里普交给我 剩下两个你自己搞定
Listen, I got Rip. You take care of the other two.
收到
Got it.
他们咬在你六点钟方向 甩掉他们
They're on your six, kid. You gotta lose them.
我在努力
I'm trying.
斯基珀 我甩不掉
Skip, I can't shake them.
右急弯 我去左边赶走里里普
Pull hard right. I'll break left and take out Rip.
- 利用那些山岩  - 明白了!
- Use the rocks.  - Roger that!
喔 喔 喔 喔!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
对了!
Yeah!
哦 这样会留疤的
Oh, that's going to leave a mark.
什么?
What?
跟华沙风车打个招呼
Say hello to the Warsaw Windmill.
- 喔! 你个疯子!  - 这就对了
- Whoa! You're crazy!  - That's right.
- 达斯迪! 你没事吧?  - 嗯 没事 我没事
- Dusty! Are you okay?  - Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
作为农用机来说很不错
That was pretty good for a crop duster.
作为不能飞的古董来说你也很不错
And not bad for an old-timer who doesn't fly.
哦 是吗? 哦 我是老 不过至少我不恐高
Oh, yeah? Well, I may be old, but at least I ain't afraid of heights.
来吧 好了
Come on, okay.
不!
No!
知道什么叫裂天者了吧!
That's why they call them Sky Slycers!
哦 不 斯基珀 你没事吧?
Oh, no. Skipper, are you okay?
你逗我么? 我好得很
Are you kidding? I'm great.
- 可是你的尾翼怎么办?  - 我没事的 去干掉他们!
- But what about your tail?  - I'll live. Go get them!
快去!
Go!
大家好 比赛已经进入最终冲刺阶段了
We're closing in on the final stretch, folks.
就是这样 科林
That's right, Colin.
自从他们从戴斯迪克沙漠出现之后
And ever since they emerged from Deadstick Desert,
里普斯林杰一直保持着领先
Ripslinger has maintained a lead.
看到他们了吗?
Any sign of them?
还没有
Nothing yet.
- 什么?  - 嗨
- What?  - Hi.
提速 提速 提速
Come on, come on, come on.
别不行啊! 别不行啊!
Not now! Not now!
提速 提速 提速
Come on, come on, come on.
不!
No!
逐风而行是无可比拟的体验
Tailwinds like nothing you've ever flown.
明白了 斯基珀
Roger that, Skip.
别往下看 别往下看
Don't look down. Don't look down.
哦 耶!
Oh. yeah!
好了 该给你看我屁股了
Okay, time to eat my dust.
看来里普斯林杰的下一个胜利近在咫尺了...
With another win for Ripslinger seeming inevitable...
等等 是农田守望者达斯迪!
Wait a second, it's Dusty Crophopper!
- 耶!  - 快去!
- Yes!  - Go!
他们来了 冲进了赛道
And here they come, down the stretch.
快到了 都有机会
It's going to be close, it's anyone's race.
好了 拍我最好看的侧面 伙计们
All right, get my good side, fellas.
什么?
What?
耶!
Yes!
他成功了! 他成功了
He's done it! He's done it.
农田守望者!
Crophopper!
不!
No!
什么?
What?
惊天逆转
From last to first.
从默默无闻到一鸣惊人
From obscurity to immortality,
赛场永远不会忘记今天
the racing world will never forget this day.
史上第一次 一架作物喷粉机
For the first time, a crop duster,
赢得了环球之翼飞行大赛!
has won the Wings Around the Globe Rally!
太好了 达斯迪! 哈... 哈!
Yes, Dusty! Ha... ha!
太棒了 达斯迪!
Magnifique, Dusty!
你真把他干掉了 伙计!
You really kicked his bottom, lad!
好啊 是! 就是这样!
All right. Yeah! Now that's how to pass!
你成功了!
You did it!
要是没有你我不会成功 多蒂
I couldn't have done it without you, Dottie.
是 我知道
Yeah, I know.
里普斯林杰喜欢对镜头耍帅的细节很重要 谢谢 楚格
Hey, buddy, great tip about Ripslinger leaning to the cameras. Thanks, Chug.
嘿 为了我兄弟
Hey, anything for my pal.
干得好 达斯迪 世界上又多了一个新的冠军
Well done, Dusty. The world has a new champion.
我心里也多了一个
And so do I.
谢谢 伊莎妮 谢你为我做的一切
Thanks, lshani. For everything.
- 达斯迪先生!  - 弗兰茨?
- Herr Dusty!  - Franz?
- 万岁!  - 你来干什么?
- Hoorah!  - What are you doing here?
我们来看你比赛 你对我们大家是一个鼓励
We came to watch you win the race. You are an inspiration to all of us.
"大家"?
"All Of us"?
对 对我们所有这些不甘于出身的人
Yeah. All of us who want to do more than just what we were built for.
喔! 谢谢 朋友们!
Whoa! Thanks, guys!
喔耶!
Whoo-wee!
里普屎林杰 真恰当 你的名字 超声波臭酱啊
Ripstinker. Yeah, that's your name. That's some supersonic sewer sauce.
伙计 我还以为维它肥够臭的了
Man, I thought Vita-stink-a-bunch was bad.
跟你比差远了
That's got nothing on you.
哦! 你真是恶心 恶心极了
Ooh! You're just nasty. Nastilicious.
你该回家洗刷洗刷了
You need to go home and wash up.
洗两次呦
Twice.
喔!
Whoa!
那个是谁?
Who's that guy?
谢谢 斯基珀
Thanks, Skip.
别谢我了
Don't thank me.
我从你身上学的比我教你的要多
I learned a lot more from you than you ever learned from me.
北太平洋某处 尼米兹级航母 飞森豪威尔号
全体立正 胜利!
Attention on deck. Victory!
胜利!
Victory!
很荣幸能来这里
It's an honor to be here.
给他们挂钩
Hook them up.
- 你准备好了吗 僚机?  - 收到
- You ready, wingman?  - Roger that.
一位光荣的乔利扳手中队成员 感觉如何 达斯迪?
An honorary Jolly Wrench. How's that feel, Dusty?
感觉很棒!
It feels great!
又回到岗位了 是吧 斯基珀?
Back in the saddle again, eh, Skipper?
哦 我上次在的时候还没有这么好的装备
Well, they didn't have these fancy toys the last time I did this.
比不了哈
Nothing to it.
他们给你们挂钩 你们向那边的发射员示意
They hook you up, you nod to the shooter over there,
准备好!
and hang on!
耶!
Yeah!
最后一个回到普罗普沃什的请客!
Last one back to Propwash buys!
哈... 哈! 来吧!
Ha... ha! You're on!